Amir Hosein Asefi Nejad

Flutter Developer

Tehran, Iran | +98 935 480 7828

p4yaam@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/payam-asefi

Sample app: https://cafebazaar.ir/app/en/com.payamasefi.olive_fa

Adaptive and curiosity-driven Flutter developer with 5 years of experience writing top-quality clean code for high-paced businesses. Leverages strong writing and debugging skills to produce engaging software. Communicates effectively with senior leadership to affect organizational change.

Skills

- Flutter | Dart
- Java | Kotlin
- BLoC pattern | SOLID principals
- Dio | SQFlite | Hive | Sensors
- Firebase | Firestore | Google Maps | ML Kit
- Unit Test | Widget Test

- Agile | Scrum
- Git | CI-CD
- Android Studio | VS Code

Experience

Mar 2018 - Present

Flutter Developer | Trinity Tech | Alayna, Turkey

- Participated in a team to re-architect and re-design an outdated large scale online marketing application using BLoC and TDD patterns.
- Solely responsible to Optimize a location-based application with more than 1000 markers which results in more than 50 percent increase in load time.
- Worked in an agile environment with the team in Iran/Turkey and have consistency met deadlines for product deliverables.
- Redesigned an application using Dart-FFI and C++ which resulted in more secure application architecture and internal API calls.

Mar 2017 - Mar 2018

Android Developer | Narin Idea Co | Tehran, Iran

- Worked as a small team led to completely re-organize and re-architect the android payment library for a Unity game with more than 20,000 active users.
- Individually implemented multiple features including one-time payment and Restful APIs.
- Analyzed an older Java application and redesigned it using MVP methodologies and Kotlin language.
- Implemented the deep links and push notifications resulted in 10 percent more Sharing Event in the application.

Oct 2015 – Feb 2017

Android Developer | Chamran University | Ahvaz, Iran

- Extensive use and implementation of the Google Map, Google Places, and OAuth APIs.
- Work as part of the team to implement VoIP technologies in a local-scale application.
- Took bottom-line responsibility for in-app notifications with the help of RESTful web services handled by backend team.
- Participated in SDLC of the application and helped create UML sequence diagrams.

Education

2008 - 2011

University of Jahad Daneshgahi of Khuzestan | Ahvaz, Iran

• BA in Information and Communication Technologies

Languages

- Persian native
- English advanced
- Deutsch beginner